<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Indore Tour</string>
    <string name="place_title">%s, Overview</string>
    <string name="lal_baagh_desc">

Resided by the rulers of the Holkar dynasty, the Lal Bagh Palace is class and grandeur personified. The palace is spread on a sprawling area of 28 acres and reflects the taste of the rulers of the Holkar dynasty.

\n\tAn example of architectural magnificence, this palace once contained one of the best rose gardens in the country.

\n\n\tAlthough Indore has its own share of grandeur, this is one spot that you should mark on the top of your travel itinerary. The palace that once was a witness to the grandeur of the Holkar dynasty, it is situated on the banks of River Khan, 3.2 km. away from the main city. The construction had begun during the time of Tukoji Rao Holkar in 1886, and completed 35 years later, by his successor Tukoji Rao Holkar in 1921. Once the residence of the ruling Holkar dynasty till 1978, it is now more of a museum, that keeps some of the most exquisite artifacts of the Maratha Empire and the Holkar dynasty intact, apart from a rare coin collection, which dates back to the Mughal period.

\n\n\tThe interiors of this palace will make you forget that you are in India, owing to the myriad mixture of Italian marble columns, grand chandeliers, rich Persian carpets, flying nymphs on the ceiling, Belgium stained glass windows, Greek mythological reliefs, Italian style wall paintings, stuffed leopards, and tigers etc. All in all, _Lal Bagh Palace is a must visit, if you\'re in Indore. Except for Monday, you can visit this palace anytime between 10:00 a.m. to 5:00 p.m. in the evening.
</string>
    <string name="rajwada_desc"> Located near the famous Kajuri Market in Indore, Rajwada is a magnificent and historical palace that is located in the city of Indore and was constructed by the Holkars more than 200 years ago. It is a seven-storied structure located near the Chhatris and serves as an excellent example of royal grandeur and architectural skills.Nestled between the crowded streets of the Kajuri Bazar and facing the main square of the city, the Rajwada palace also faces a well-maintained garden that houses a statue of Queen Ahilya Bai, an artificial waterfall and some beautiful fountains. Even after all these years, the palace continues to be one of the most famous tourist spots in Indore and is one of the oldest structures too. </string>
    <string name="city_shpooing_desc"> Being the commercial capital of Madhya Pradesh, Indore witnesses many business activities on a daily basis. This city resembles Mumbai regarding its trade and commerce. Since Indore is well connected to Mumbai, the trade of both the cities resembles. One can go on a shopping spree in the city and enjoy the experience to the fullest. Shopaholics get an amazing experience at the place. The city has a range of shops ranging from street shops to branded showrooms.The markets of Indore have a variety of items to offer to the customers. There are numerous shops to buy from in Indore. International stores and showrooms are a part of the marketplace as well. The cloth industry of Indore too is quite famous. Fabrics are beautifully decorated with hand block printing, tie, dye and zari work.People staying here absolutely adore the Maheshwari and Chanderi sarees of the city. One can also select from the variety of local crafts present in the place. Shop till you drop is one saying which is taken very seriously in this place with so many place and commodities to choose from. </string>
    <string name="kanch_mandire_desc">Made entirely out of glass, this Jain Temple exhibits exquisite artwork on glass panels depicting the various aspects of Jainism. The intricate detailing on the glass reflects the talent and dedication of the artists.</string>
    <string name="bada_ganapati_desc">In Hindi, \'Bada\' literally means big, and Ganpati is the pet name of elephant-faced god Lord Ganesha. This temple earns its name due to the size of Lord Ganesha\'s idol - at the height of about 25 feet from crown to foot, it is said to be one of the largest idols of the God in the world. The statue is made of a peculiar mixture of limestone, jaggery, bricks and sacred soil and water from the major pilgrim places in the country. Located at the end of a quiet lane in the city of Indore, the Bada Ganpati may be a modest-looking temple, but it holds significance simply based on the enormity of the Lord\'s statue.There are conflicting accounts of how the sacred abode came into existence. Established in the year 1875 by Shri Dadich, the construction of Bada Ganpati Temple was brought about by the family members Holkar Dynasty, the rulers of the region then. The Queen Ahilya Bai Holkar undertook the project under her wing more than 100 years ago. Ganpati is said to be the bringer of happiness and prosperity. The Lord is worshipped at the beginning of any new event, venture, or pooja in the entire nation. Devotees from all over the world come to Indore to visit this statue which has a high religious significance.Devotees of Ganpati should definitely have this temple on their itinerary. It is especially ideal during the festive season when there is a constant celebration through poojas and sweet offerings to the Lord Ganesha in the hope of seeking blessings for peace, prosperity, and well-being.</string>
    <string name="annapurna_temple_desc">The Annapurna Temple, besides being a place for pilgrimages is also a tourist attraction. Dedicated to Goddess Annapurna, the deity of food the temple also houses the shrines of Sivan, Hanuman and Kalabhairava.The entrance of the temple is adorned with four-life size statues of elephants, and the architectural splendour of the temple makes it a must-visit for all tourists.</string>
    <string name="chhappan_dukaan_desc">Chhappan Dukaan is one of Indore\'s choicest street food hubs that serve specials, chaat, idli and dosa with equal gusto. Chhappan Dukaan literally means fifty-six shops. At the time when it was established, 56 separate shops were started here, all selling food items. The evenings light the place up like nothing else with people consuming the delectable spread with enthusiasm.</string>
    <string name="gomat_giri_desc">A pilgrimage site for the Jains, Gomatgiri is located at a distance of merely 10-minutes drive from the Indore airport. A 21 ft statue of Gomateshwar which is a replica of the gigantic statue of Bahubali at Shravanabelagola is a major attraction. The statue of Gomateshwar is situated at a hill. Apart from this, there are also 24 temples, each representing the 24 Tirthankaras of Jainism. Gomatgiri is a picnic spot that will reward you with the best views of the area.</string>
    <string name="chhatris_desc">The cremation places of the Holkars are known as the Chhatris. These are beautifully built and have intricately carved structures. There are some temples and other structures built around them as well.</string>
    <string name="khajrana_temple_desc">The Khajrana Ganesh temple is one of the most powerful shrines of the Lord Ganesha. It was built by Rani Ahilyabai Holkar to safeguard the idol of Lord Ganesha from Aurangzeb. The temple has since grown from being housed in a small hut to a big temple with large inner and outer sanctums. Vinayak Chaturthi is celebrated in a big way in the temple.</string>
    <string name="sarafa_desc">The lip-smacking flavours of the food stalls in Sarafa Bazaar are a testimony to Indore\'s legendary love affair with food. Entertaining over 3000 visitors every day, the Sarafa Bazaar houses stalls that sell vividly coloured artificial jewellery, brass ornaments and mouth-watering dishes of the diverse cuisine of Indore. There are more than 50 dishes available here at extremely low rates.</string>
    <string name="rang_panchami_desc"> An extension of Holi called Rang Panchmi is a very famous festival in Indore and few tens of thousands of people gather in front of Rajwada and surrounding areas to get colored by the famous color cannon</string>
    <string name="patal_pani_desc">Plummeting from a height of 300 meters, the Patalpani Waterfall is the most scenic photo stop in Indore. These roaring falls are enveloped by refreshing mist and dense verdure making them the favourite getaway picnic spot. The monsoons swell the falls and may make it risky for close encounters causing accidents. It is best to maintain cautious distance from the waterfall during the rains.</string>
    <string name="pipliyapala_desc">Spreading over an area of a whopping 122 acres and housing a ginormous 80-acre lake, the Pipliyapala Regional Park is an absolute treat for adults and children alike. Engage in some fun-filled activities like pedal-boating and motor-boating and witness the magical allure of the Mist and Musical Fountain, French Gardens, Labyrinths, Artist Village, etc. Be sure to try the savoury delicacies available at the Fast Food Zone.</string>
    <string name="iskcon_desc">Let the melodies of Shri Krishna\' soothing hymns and let its vibrations heal you at ISKCON Indore. The mesmerizingly beautiful deities of Radha and Krishna are made purely from marble and invoke a sense of calm within you. The celebration of Janmashtami at ISKCON Indore is an occasion of pomp and splendour galore.</string>
    <string name="indore_white_church_desc">A peek into the impact of British autonomy on Indore pre-independence, the Indore White Church is one of the most significant points of interest of the city. A testimony to awe-striking European architecture, the entire structure is made of milk white stone and marble. To witness the church in all its glory during Christmas, decorated from head to toe, is a sight for sore eyes.</string>
    <string name="ralamandal_desc">The oldest sanctuary of Madhya Pradesh, the Ralamandal Wildlife Sanctuary packs a treat for wildlife and avifauna enthusiasts alike. The River Narmada, which is 150 million years older than River Ganga, graces the sanctuary with its presence. Home to deer, wild hare, tigers and an umpteen variety of birds, this sanctuary is nothing short of paradise.</string>
    <string name="bijasen_tekri_desc">Perched upon the Tekri Hill, the Bijasen Tekri temple offers picturesque views of the entire city and the magnanimous hill ranges. The power of Mata here is so strong, that it is believed to bring back sight in the eyes of the blind! The infamous Navratri Mela held here sees a traffic of thousands of devotees and tourists each year.</string>
    <string name="nehru_park_desc"> The Kamala Nehru Park, popularly known as Chidiya Ghar, is a zoological park on the outskirts of Indore that is home to exotic carnivores, awe-striking amphibians and vividly colourful avifauna. New addition to the family is a white tigress and her three cubs! You can enjoy buggy rides, pony rides, elephant rides and camel rides here too.</string>
    <string name="kamal_nehru_desc">Home to the majestic Bengal Tigers and the awe-striking White Tigers, the Kamla Nehru Prani Sanghrahalay does a great deal at protecting and breeding these rare beautiful creatures. It also houses the humungous Himalayan Black Bears, Leopards and many endangered amphibians and avifauna. The zoo is soon going to be home to one of the largest reptiles of the planet - the anaconda.</string>
    <string name="indore_musem_desc">Exhibiting artefacts dating as far back to the prehistoric era, as well as recent findings from the modern era, the Central Museum of Indore is a history buff\'s paradise. The museum also houses mythological carvings, coins from different ages, arms of various eras and sculptures dating back to the 11th century. Be sure to check the rare dried botanical creatures on display too!</string>
    <string name="meghdoot_garden_desc">Meghdoot Gardens or Meghdoot Upavan is one of the oldest gardens of Indore, but its glory has only augmented with time. Luxuriously dense landscapes with different shades of green decorate the premises of the garden and make up the perfect environment to relax and rejuvenate. The park is dotted with beautiful misty fountains and also has a special children\'s play area</string>
    <string name="mohandi_falls_desc">The breathtaking sight of water falling from a height is always thrilling, and Mohadi Waterfalls are just the perfect spot where you would take your family to visit for a picnic. Easily accessible, the Waterfall is located at a distance of 30 kms from Indore, it is an idyllic picnic spot if you are looking for a break from the monotony of life and want to be with your family.</string>
    <string name="geeta_bhavan_desc">Geeta Bhawan is a religious shrine in Indore but is one of its kind. The shrine is in fact religiously neutral and welcomes people of all spiritual faiths to lighten their hearts. The pristine place houses pictures and idols of many different gods and is decorated with the paintings of the epic Puranas, Mahabharata and Ramayana.</string>
    <string name="gandhi_hall_desc">A testament of awe-striking Indo-Gothic architecture, the Gandhi Hall was named so after the passing of our great father of the nation - Mahatma Gandhi. Made of white marble and Seoni and red stones, the grandiose of this monument is simply majestic. The venue for huge public celebrations, the hall can accommodate more than 2000 people and also houses the city\'s famous watch tower.</string>
    <string name="tincha_fall_desc">Located 25 kilometres from the bustling city of Indore, Tincha Falls are one of the most popular waterfalls in the region. The milky white cascade is located in the Tincha village, also where the falls derive their name from. The roaring plunge of water at a height of 300 feet is a rain fed waterfall and is primarily a monsoon destination. Surrounded by lush green vegetation on all sides and an exhilarating experience in itself,Tincha falls attracts a wide array of visitors from all walks of life. The falls are also a canyon, nuzzled in between valleys Tincha is an ideal picnic destination and monsoon break away from the chaos that ensues in the cities. The falls also have a small pond near the foot of the falls, the stillness of the pond against the roaring descent of water is a sight you must definitely not miss.</string>
    <string name="patalpani_desc">The Patalpani Waterfall is located in the Mhow Tehsil of Indore district and is a popular picnic spot for the locals of the area. Surrounded by dense forest covers, majestic hills, clear skies and lush green landscapes Patalpani is perfect for anyone looking for a time out from their mundane schedules. The falls are at a height of 300 feet and produce roaring streams of white when the water flow is at its full capacity. The waterflow is magnanimous during the monsoons and slopes may become slippery and treacherous, so the visitors are advised to exercise precaution during their tour of the falls. All in all the Patalpani falls are truly a sight to behold in all their plunging glory, the majestic cascade is a must visit for anyone who enjoys nature.</string>
    <string name="bamniya_kund_desc">Bamniya Kund is a captivating waterfall 50 kms from Indore in Madhya Pradesh. Falling from a height of 300 feet, the waters gush down creating a colourful pool of clear blue waters, brown rocks and verdant green bushes. Nestled away in the depth of dense forests in the Malindi region near Indore, the waterfall is hidden away from the clearing. You will have to reach the Nakheri Dam at the base of the hill and the cascading waters are still a considerably long trek away. The trekking trail however, is marked through the beautiful woods and the you can spot several birds, animals and exotic plants native to the region. The waterfalls are a delight to the naked eye and a must visit place if you are in the area.</string>
    <string name="dharampuri_desc">Dharampuri is a quaint little town filled with historical gems in the Dhar district of Madhya Pradesh set along the banks of river Narmada, was also said to be the birthplace and abode of Narmada’s daughter Roopmati who married the ruler of Mandu; Baz Bahadur. The town was established by the oldest Pandava; Yudhishthir and is rich in legends and folklores, all adding to its ancient charm and mystery. It is a gateway into the eventful lives of celebrated kings and queens that resided here centuries ago, also home to some stunning architectural marvels of medieval period, Dharampuri is a treasure cove tucked away in to a cosy little town neck that has been a residence to a plethora of Emperors and fostered their tales of benevolence and fortitude.</string>
    <string name="choral_dam_desc">If you are tired of the pell mell of the daily life and want to go away to unwind and relax, Choral Dam is just the place for you. Located in the state of Madhya Pradesh, Choral Dam is a hidden gem that will definitely provide you with quietness and tranquility. Constructed around the backwaters of River Narmada, Choral Dam is replete with cool and clear water. A large number of lush green trees and small hills surround the place making it even more attractive. This place is full of jovial water activities that will interest young and old alike. The panoramic views of the sky and the ground are mesmerizing. To enjoy nature at its best make sure to witness either a sunset or a sunrise from here. The different hues of sky coupled with the verdant trees and clear blue water is nothing short of perfection. Choral Dam is an ideal place for a weekend getaway and spend some quiet time relaxing and unwinding.</string>
    <string name="janapav_desc"> Nestled among similar hills of the Malwa region, Janapav, or Janapav Kuti, is the ideal getaway for lovers of nature and trekkers alike. If you’re looking to traverse through twisty bends in Central Indian forests while peacefully gazing over distant hills and the crimson sunset, then this hill station should be your destination. Located on the Mumbai-Indore highway and in the Mhow Tehsil of Indore district, Janapav experiences footfall from all areas of country throughout the year, especially during monsoons.

Situated as it is at a height of 881 m, 45 km away from the city of Indore, and surrounded by forest cover, Janapav is a pocket of nature whose air will not only cleanse your lungs but also leave you spiritually soothed. Indeed the flora of this region is known for its unique Ayurvedic potencies and is accordingly harvested by expert Ayurveda practitioners. The place is also famous for the fair a that is held there every year on Kartik Purnima which is the first full moon after Diwali.</string>
<string name="hanuwantiya_desc">Hanuwantiya is one of the island amongst the archipelago situated in the Indira Sagar river. This place is vibrant and colourful that will surely be a good break from the hustle bustle of the city life. Hanuwantiya island is full of scenic beauty and the cool water that surrounds this island is an added bonus. The adventurous activities and the serenity of this place will makes this place a great holiday destination. During the Jal Mahotsava, this place is thronging with people and the colourful kites and hot air balloons that fly ornate the sky making the whole place look mesmerizing.</string>

<string name="royal_museum_desc">Royal Museum of Indore is a tiny museum famous for housing a collection of thrones, photographs and weapons etc. Most of these artefacts belong to the 19th century which was under the rule of Serfoji II. </string>
<string name="kanha_museum_desc">Kanha Museum is a small museum in Indore especially dedicated to wild life, reptiles study etc. In addition to that, it also has artefacts related to the past and history of Indore. </string>
<string name="chhatri_bagh_desc">Located at Shree Nagar in Indore, Chhatri Bagh was originally a burial site for an ancient Holkar King which has now been turned into a popular park. The park has a lot of canopied aka chhatris which mark the burial site of a Holkar king or queen.</string>
<string name="chidiya_bhadak_fall_desc">Chidiya Bhadak Falls is one of the unexplored and secret gem of Indore. Enveloped in lush greenery, and rocky cliffs, the waterfalls is a mesmerizing sight to watch and is a picture worth capturing. The waterfall also offer good trekking and hiking opportunities.</string>
<string name="gidiya_khoh_waterfall_desc">Gidiya Khoh Waterfall is situated near Indore and is essentially a monsoon fed waterfall. Hence the most ideal time to visit the waterfall is during the rainy season to experience the gurgling rush of water in all its glory and splendour. </string>
<string name="jogi_bhadak_waterfall_desc">Jogi Bhadak is a local waterfall situated in Dhal near Indore. It is one of the most charming and mesmerising waterfalls near the city. The waterfalls also provides various trekking and hiking opportunities and some adventure activities.</string>
    <string name="share">Share</string>
    <string name="explore_more">Read More!</string>
    <string name="no_one_indore">No.1 \nIndore</string>

</resources>


